<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hard Like Algebra</title>
    <description>Because it&#39;s all about the music and art and people and.....</description>
    <link>http://hardlikealgebra.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://hardlikealgebra.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>You&#39;re not punk and I&#39;m telling everyone</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/jawbreaker.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Jawbreaker playing at Riot Fest&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just got home from seeing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dontbreakdown.com/&quot;&gt;the Jawbreaker documentary&lt;/a&gt;, and first off, it was incredible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mean, music movies are my jam, the same way some folks like Lifetime movies or all the albums Jade Tree put out in the late 90’s. Know me long enough and I’ll try to make you watch &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0077838/&quot;&gt;the Last Waltz&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0106880/?ref_=nv_sr_1&quot;&gt;Fear of a Black Hat&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0195909/?ref_=nv_sr_1&quot;&gt;Meeting People is Easy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But an interesting thing about this movie is that it reflected my relationship with the band: I don’t know a ton of their songs, but the ones I know gut me. Choke me up. I mean:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This is a story you won’t tell the kids we’ll never have.&lt;br /&gt;
If you hear this song a hundred times it still won’t be enough.&lt;br /&gt;
– “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iP1lJRcEfEI&quot;&gt;Sluttering (May 4th)&lt;/a&gt;”    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A near miss or a close call?&lt;br /&gt;
I keep a room at the hospital.&lt;br /&gt;
I scratch my accidents into the wall.&lt;br /&gt;
– “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=T4BlLskdYtg&quot;&gt;Accident Prone&lt;/a&gt;”  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I have a present: it is the present.&lt;br /&gt;
You have to learn to find it within you.&lt;br /&gt;
If you could save yourself,&lt;br /&gt;
you could save us all.&lt;br /&gt;
Go on living, prove us wrong.&lt;br /&gt;
“&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=v1ZNZ_G9llQ&quot;&gt;Save Your Generation&lt;/a&gt;”)  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These songs hit me so, so hard. And it turns out they are all from the album that basically killed the band.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-CKiR7DYGxk&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dear You&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; was their major label debut. They were on Geffen, and had Green Day’s producer, video director, etc. etc. The label thought they’d &lt;em&gt;be&lt;/em&gt; the next Green Day. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…and then the album sold 40,000 copies. Label didn’t give a fuck about them anymore, the punks got pissed because they “sold out” (and because the album sounded so much more produced), they got fed up with each other, and they quit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a moment in the movie when someone said “man, if this album came out in 1998, it would have been gigantic.” I think about 1998 – I would have firmly been in my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=srU0xhkfIFw&quot;&gt;Promise Ring&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=N6aJET24Auw&quot;&gt;Fifteen&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fbRQieiX1H0&quot;&gt;Propagandhi&lt;/a&gt; phase – and I think, “hell yeah this woulda been all I listened to!” I have a good friend that always contended this would be my gateway Jawbreaker album, and it’s slowly becoming that. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I say slowly because the dirty secret is that even though I got to see Jawbreaker do their heralded Riot Fest performance AND went to this screening (attended by Jawbreaker bassist Chris, who lives in Olympia and works at a food bank), my knowledge of them is slight. The songs that I know well are songs that I fucking adore; I still think “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iP1lJRcEfEI&quot;&gt;Sluttering (May 4th)&lt;/a&gt;” deserves to be part of the “oh god” double A side 7” that would include the Mountain Goats “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Vm-NW1RwPY8&quot;&gt;No Children&lt;/a&gt;” on the other side and be the single greatest fucked up breakup single ever. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I moved to my own apartment recently, my first time ever living alone (no partner, no dog). Something told me that I should buy a copy of &lt;em&gt;Dear You&lt;/em&gt; to listen to while I unpacked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did, and I was right. And seeing those songs on the big screen – about two months since my landlord handed me my keys – made me say “oh my god” out loud.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jawbreaker has been a slow burn for me, and I still know way more Jets to Brazil (Blake’s later band) songs by heart than I do Jawbreaker songs. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I think it’s starting to take.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;When you’re an extrovert who lives alone, you talk to yourself a lot. &lt;em&gt;A lot&lt;/em&gt;. Then, when you’re out in the world &lt;em&gt;you have forgotten how to notice you’re still talking to yourself out loud.&lt;/em&gt; So that’s a fun thing. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://hardlikealgebra.com/2017/10/23/jawbreaker/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hardlikealgebra.com/2017/10/23/jawbreaker/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>It was Twenty Years Ago Today</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;me and a giant OKNOTOK19972017 poster&quot; src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jwithington/jwithington.github.io/master/images/070817-radiohead-poster.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mention my mom a lot as far as my source of music. Not necessarily the things I listen to – though I long ago made peace with loving &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iUAYeN3Rp2E&quot;&gt;Chicago&lt;/a&gt; and “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rPJz3syNbtE&amp;amp;list=RDrPJz3syNbtE&quot;&gt;Rock Steady&lt;/a&gt;,” to name a few – but the sort of obsessive, HOLY SHIT IT IS THIS SONG TIME TO TELL YOU ALL ABOUT IT side of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can remember days in our (stupidly hot) Chevy Van, windows open, mom listening to the AM oldies station&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; (&lt;em&gt;AGAIIIN&lt;/em&gt;, MOM?) while driving to go shopping or take me to a doctor’s appointment or whatever. Song came on that she loved (for real, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.guitarplayer.com/artists/1013/hear-terry-kaths-isolated-guitar-from-chicagos-25-or-6-to-4/56811&quot;&gt;Chicago&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, and talking would cease, because she’d &lt;em&gt;throw&lt;/em&gt; the volume up and sing along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now might be a good time to mention that I also claim my singing voice came from my dad (who played baseball, but also was in at least one high school musical), not from her. That would be mean, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was 9 years old, she got particularly excited on one specific day, though.  I couldn’t understand why, but her radio station kept playing the same stupid Beatles&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; song, over and over and over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No, Jim, you don’t understand!  This is Sgt. Pepper’s! They said 20 years ago today – and it’s 20 years ago, &lt;em&gt;today&lt;/em&gt;!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is probably the first music nerd thing I remember, and likely made me the insufferable/hopeful sometimes insightful music fan I am, now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She’s nearly 70 now, and has just gotten a new turntable set up to replace the component-based monster she hadn’t set up for years (and eventually gave away?).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When they reissued Sgt. Pepper’s a few weeks ago, and I heard &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.merlinmann.com/roderick/ep-247-george-martins-butt.html&quot;&gt;John and Merlin raving about it&lt;/a&gt;, I knew I wanted a copy. But more than that, I knew I wanted to send her  a copy. I did, and in typical mom fashion, she parceled out listening to it for a few days.  She had TV she didn’t want to miss, and geese to chase away from her yard, but I also think she wanted to savor it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I got my new turntable, that was the first album I played on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sent her a text today, the day after I picked up &lt;em&gt;OKNOTOK19972017&lt;/em&gt;, the reissue of &lt;em&gt;OK Computer&lt;/em&gt;.  Told her how I remember her excitement about 20 years of Sgt. Pepper’s, and left off the part where, shit, I have those moments when I wish I had a nine year old I could yell about OK Computer with (hmm, maybe I should call my niece and shout at her about it?). I told mom what I wrote here – that I think it’s kinda cool that these two albums will always be linked in their anniversaries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I told her I might send her a copy of this one, too, and “break your brain a bit. 😜 💜”. I still might, and that breaks my brain a bit, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;texts between me and my mom&quot; src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jwithington/jwithington.github.io/master/images/070817-mom-radiohead-text.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;She hated FM &lt;strong&gt;SO MUCH&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;As Rob Thomas pointed out during his Rock and Roll Hall of Fame induction speech last week, Chicago aren’t exactly the coolest band in the world. “People say a lot of things about Chicago,” he said. “And I know that ‘badass’ generally is not one of them, but just remember that when Jimi Hendrix met them for the first time he told them that their horn section sounded like one set of lungs and their guitar player Terry [Kath] was better than him. That, kids, is badass. If you think Chicago is your mom’s band, then man, I want to party with your mom.” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rollingstone.com/music/news/flashback-chicago-play-a-smoldering-25-or-6-to-4-in-1970-20160412&quot;&gt;https://www.rollingstone.com/music/news/flashback-chicago-play-a-smoldering-25-or-6-to-4-in-1970-20160412&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I HATED the Beatles as a kid. I still hate the early stuff that’s more “oldies station” than “whoaaaa how’d they do that?” &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://hardlikealgebra.com/2017/07/08/twenty-years-ago/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hardlikealgebra.com/2017/07/08/twenty-years-ago/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What I’ve been doing; or,</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/nest-on-books-on-shelf.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A nest on top of a stack of books, on a bookshelf&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-ive-been-doing-or-what-if-you-start-a-project-and-it-kinda-takes-off-but-doesnt-or-what-if-it-seems-like-you-abandoned-your-own-thing-or-integrating-new-practices-or-day-36-to-day-64&quot;&gt;What I’ve been doing; or, what if you start a project and it kinda takes off but doesn’t; or, what if it seems like you abandoned your own thing; or, integrating new practices; or, Day 36 to Day 64&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the first 5 weeks or so of 2017, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jwithington/100-days-of-healthing/graphs/commit-activity&quot;&gt;I committed a whole lot&lt;/a&gt; to my #&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jwithington/100-days-of-healthing&quot;&gt;100DaysOfHealthing repo&lt;/a&gt;. The project buzzed around my head, I set up my work computer to launch Git Bash every day when I logged in, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://selfcare.tech/&quot;&gt;folks that I admire&lt;/a&gt; even added me to their &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jenniferlynparsons/selfcaretech/pull/36&quot;&gt;own projects&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then hey look at that, it was February, and a lot of good things were happening in my personal life–health things shaking out, finances slowly but kinda surely improving, meditating every day (not just three minutes at a time, but 10 minutes, even! Thanks &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.headspace.com&quot;&gt;Headspace&lt;/a&gt; !), and going to acupuncture regularly. I took baths a lot more with the help of the “podcast bath kit” my girlfriend bought me for Christmas. I helped promote self-care at work and at home. I had encouraging things for other folks who were participating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then, the commits dried up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel a responsibility to explain that, and also like the idea of showing how &lt;em&gt;this kind of shift&lt;/em&gt; can be positive, too.  So here goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;you-are-not-your-projects&quot;&gt;You are not your projects&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You know what would suck? If &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;trying to get one self-care hour a day stressed you the fuck out&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. If trying to make time to track a self-care hour &lt;em&gt;in itself made you miss or long for self-care&lt;/em&gt;. If “update self-care log” because a niggling, nagging task, instead of a joyous way to track amazing steps!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did this happen to me? No way. But as I started updating three, four, seven days all in a batch, I realized something:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It was more important to me to live a life that included self-care (and promotion of self-care) than it was to do little updates every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cop out? Hmm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;¯\_(ツ)_/¯&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But here’s a list of things that have happened since my last commit to the repo:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For my birthday, my girlfriend, dog, and &lt;strong&gt;I took a screenless weekend on the Washington coast&lt;/strong&gt;. This included a lot of taking baths, reading, and not much else. I wanted a pause, and I got one, and it was like a self-care boot camp reset.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I learned that &lt;strong&gt;I no longer wanted to use my phone as my alarm&lt;/strong&gt;. Weird? I dunno, but hear me out: screenless weekend meant my phone wasn’t the last thing I saw at light’s out or the first thing I saw when waking up. I no longer could get sucked in to distractions at the time when my mind is most apt (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3MpRt41tPoc&quot;&gt;apt!&lt;/a&gt;) to fill with distraction.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;So I bought a [Pebble Time][pebble]. This, too, was huge. Now I had an alarm that would wake me up silently, more easily, and without  HEY HERE’S ALL THE COOL PHONE THINGS YOU CAN DO staring at me from moment one. I can walk the dog without my phone as a step tracker. I have a thing that lives on my body that maybe is a bit less accurate but more realistic in telling me when I was &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; sleeping.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I continued working out some medication stuff that’s important.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I had some mini-breakthroughs in therapy and at acupuncture.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These seem positive to me. And (maybe with the exception of a gadget, even a well-thought out one) it seems like ongoing self-care, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;unstructured-time&quot;&gt;Unstructured Time&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I never take any. If I think of the kind of thing where I actively just…hang out? Watch a random movie? Read a magazine and just drink coffee, or even just go out for coffee without a Task At Hand? I hardly ever do these things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And my therapist (who rules) and I keep coming back to that. I always feel &lt;a href=&quot;http://5by5.tv/b2w/251&quot;&gt;time-constrained&lt;/a&gt;, and I also always feel like “this time right here has to have something going on.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, in a way, I’ve been doing more self-care during #100DaysOfHealthing. I just haven’t always planned, executed and recorded it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope that’s true for you as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I know that I have a loooong way to go improve my relationship with myself and others, but the self-care part has landed in a good spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;now-what&quot;&gt;Now What?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, a few things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I still consider the project to be underway, for me, and for any of you that are still doing it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In the future, for the project, I’m going to consider finding a way to make tracking days a lot simpler / more “on the fly”. Because stressing out about tracking self-care is super unproductive.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;At some point we will reach 100 days!  And then maybe, later in the year, I’ll do a relaunch of the project.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But for now, know this: I’m supporting myself by taking time for self-care. I hope you are, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;❤️
jim&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;p.s. I wrote this about two weeks ago, but didn’t quite post it then. I think it all still stands though. 😀 Today, March 18, is Day 75, if you’re counting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;small&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post originally appeared on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unfocused.tech/&quot;&gt;unfocused.tech&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;You should go &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.marinacottages.com/&quot;&gt;to Westport&lt;/a&gt;. It’s delightful. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://hardlikealgebra.com/2017/03/18/100-days-update/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hardlikealgebra.com/2017/03/18/100-days-update/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>10 Fun Facts About Utah!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/nancynance/22725566840/in/photolist-ACbtgW-dnMeeW-5CRmz3-8BessX-8DnojG-ncz1nJ-5RKBgj-cs4dRQ-MpExdY-sbShsT-faNC7Q-pX3HKF-styaci-ncphhE-NnB11a-dF9Db4-epqJ9e-8Tt5DJ-saF4LX-bqust5-HMdgTm-KW7yua-oWtz3U-y6ZhQM-gfr3fH-JmXDH2-KAeimu-FafAko-HsSifG-G46Qyj-JzEa6F-6Mj8j5-5hmETi-bwezf5-dZoEsd-J8JWMQ-vHFmHw-Jp8W9U-wooYjT-BUXasg-HL7ZHG-FXxNQT-JwxSkN-GQ8xCQ-G8wqUx-GQgiAi-K2VRUt-Jy2wrT-JrgthQ-J5nyx5&quot; title=&quot;welcome to Utah&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://c1.staticflickr.com/1/582/22725566840_0caa47527a_h.jpg&quot; width=&quot;1600&quot; height=&quot;901&quot; alt=&quot;welcome to Utah&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
# 10 Fun Facts about Utah!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It was founded by the Utes, a gang of kids that lived in Joe Pesci’s neighborhood.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Morton Salt has their headquarters there, and the rebranding of a toxic salt spill to be a Great Salt Lake is studied in marketing programs around the world.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Mountain Time Zone was named after Big Mountain Jones, a local goldsmith in the 1800s.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The NBA’s Utah Jazz are named the Jazz because Salt Lake City is known as the Birthplace of Jazz. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Famous Jazz player Karl Malone is nicknamed the Mailman, because when he first started playing in the NBA, he also drove for USPS to help make ends meet.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Another famous Jazz in Utah: DJ Jazzy Jeff summers in Park City.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The University of Utah offers the world’s only BFA in Snowboarding.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Children from all over Utah compete annually in the nation’s largest staring contest, judged by Nickelodeon’s Pete and Pete.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;While alcohol content is kept under 4% for draft beer, Utah is the nation’s only state where bottles of unknown hooch with “XXX” on them are still legal. Locals call it Ramble Gamble Juice!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’ma be there in about 14 hours for MARCH MADNESS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://hardlikealgebra.com/2017/03/15/utah/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hardlikealgebra.com/2017/03/15/utah/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>100 Days of Healthing</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/sachac/16691122547/in/photostream/&quot; title=&quot;2015-03-18c What do I do for self-care -- index card #self-care #happiness #comfort&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://c4.staticflickr.com/9/8726/16691122547_9348647318_z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;383&quot; alt=&quot;2015-03-18c What do I do for self-care -- index card #self-care #happiness #comfort&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-this-now&quot;&gt;What’s this, now?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspired by &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.freecodecamp.com/join-the-100daysofcode-556ddb4579e4#.c2c5pd1h2&quot;&gt;100DaysofCode&lt;/a&gt;, 100 Days of Healthing is a challenge to spend an hour a day, for 100 days, working on your health &amp;amp; self care. It’s permission to give &lt;em&gt;yourself&lt;/em&gt; an hour a day. And we’re all here with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-do-you-hate-100-days-of-code&quot;&gt;Why do you hate 100 Days of Code?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh my goodness, that’s so not true!  I don’t. I think it’s a fabulous concept, super motivating, something I want to do (maybe for the second 100 days of 2017?) and something that could be done alongside 100 Days of Healthing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ka11away&quot;&gt;Alex&lt;/a&gt; is an inspiration – I even forked &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jwithington/100-days-of-healthing&quot;&gt;my Github repo&lt;/a&gt; from him! Without 100 Days of Code, this new project isn’t a thing. His framework allowed me to envision this, and I’m super grateful for that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-thing-is-though&quot;&gt;The thing is, though….&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coding and health aren’t mutually exclusive&lt;/strong&gt;.  We can keep our skills fresh &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; take care of our minds, bodies, and spirits. Things like &lt;a href=&quot;http://selfcare.tech&quot;&gt;selfcare.tech&lt;/a&gt;  are &lt;em&gt;vital and necessary&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those of us who work in tech often do it because we have untreated/undiagnosed health issues, communication troubles, or other things that make tech work line up with our needs. There’s nothing wrong with that either – I’m a huge advocate for employers that recognize that adults need to go to the doctor during work hours, or that just know that people need to work from home because they are &lt;a href=&quot;https://butyoudontlooksick.com/articles/written-by-christine/the-spoon-theory/&quot;&gt;out of spoons&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;and-sometimes&quot;&gt;And sometimes?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes getting lost in the screen to. Just. Flash. Another. Version. Of. Android.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Or &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; get a new Jekyll droplet going. Or &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; finish that &lt;strong&gt;one&lt;/strong&gt; ticket “so we can go home.” Sometimes those things are taxing! And so it goes that the health issues and communication and all those other important things just never get addressed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I started wondering: What if the same kind of momentum built when a bunch of people turn their attention to coding could happen around health? What if you sorta got that dopamine jolt of “yep, it’s a new day, I gotta get my hour of self care?” What if the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.freecodecamp.com/&quot;&gt;FreeCodeCamp&lt;/a&gt; community could rally behind this, too?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/sachac/17157051896/in/photolist-s97nMA-sfUoL1-9sa2eX-9sd1LL-aatdKM-6PEeVj-dsx3i6-cJYTJC-oMzPb-56CUnd-9sgfe9-fsXK2T-pihpVY-qgL4mF-4f7bev-9TfaLW-ej2mct-gwmN7H-a9MFqY-gwmAC2-jSWVy4-eg9yha-dswhG8-9sgf6f-4FSfTU-aBshrA-nbuAHY-nAKQ4C-zMGBS-9sa2pR-9sge2w-nbtLM7-9sdfhX-jgW5dc-dFHiG5-r1jJAM-6EpzvX-7E3U4g-cjF8mq-5jhfU6-fZDKXs-5HCzhP-9sge6s-drgpAM-9sdfFD-9sgeD5-9FFDea-dPyiC6-9sgfeY-9sdfxp/&quot; title=&quot;2015-04-17b Being extra-kind to myself -- index card #self-care&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://c1.staticflickr.com/8/7669/17157051896_4dac889f84_z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;383&quot; alt=&quot;2015-04-17b Being extra-kind to myself -- index card #self-care&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-your-personal-story&quot;&gt;What’s your personal story?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, I’m learning a lot of stuff about my mental and physical health right now, and it’s taking a lot of time and scheduling and effort and stuff like that. I realllly wanted to sign up for the new wave of #100DaysOfCode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However! One thing I’m getting better at is knowing what I can and cannot do, and I realized that I actually &lt;em&gt;need to get better at my own self-care&lt;/em&gt; before I can use that time for something like coding an hour outside of work every day. The #100DaysofHealthing project represents me acknowledging that, while also wanting to do a thing for 100 days and hopefully share that thing with others.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;okay-cool-how-do-i-do-it&quot;&gt;Okay, cool. How do I do it?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Work on your health and self care for &lt;em&gt;at least an hour a day&lt;/em&gt;, starting on January 3, 2017.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To track your progress, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jwithington/100-days-of-healthing&quot;&gt;fork this repo&lt;/a&gt;. Or consult the FAQ’s below.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make a public commitment to the challenge. Use the hashtag #100DaysOfHealthing (preferably on Twitter) to announce your intentions.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tweet about your progress every day using the hashtag. I will, too, over &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/jwithy&quot;&gt;@jwithy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’ll push my progress to Github every day, and so can you! Follow it &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jwithington/100-days-of-healthing&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;some-notes-and-what-have-yous&quot;&gt;Some notes and what-have-yous&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t put yourself at risk.&lt;/strong&gt; This is important. For a coding project, you shouldn’t be vague; for health, you might need to be.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:4&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:4&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; That’s cool. Don’t disclose anything that you wouldn’t tell your family, your boss, your loved ones, or that dude who was a jerk to you in high school. “Completed my hour of self-care!” isn’t vague – it’s acknowledging that some things need to stay private. See the FAQ’s for more.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What constitutes self-care and health?&lt;/strong&gt; Well, that can totally vary from person to person, but here are some ways I think of it:
&lt;br /&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Going to the doctor for something you’ve been putting off, or that requires ongoing attention.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Meditating, praying, anything like that!&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Do you need permission to play a video game that totally helps you wind down after a hard day? You’ve got it!&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Are you addicted to said video game? Well, maybe reading a book instead would help your self care.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Diagnosed with a thing? Reading about strategies to cope, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC-nPM1_kSZf91ZGkcgy_95Q&quot;&gt;watching videos that help you learn a thing&lt;/a&gt;, going to a support group…these are all healthing!&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;What do you want to do that makes you feel like a better you? Coloring? Knitting? Cooking something for friends? Scented candles and tea? Do it do it do it. An hour for you.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hey I don’t work in tech.&lt;/strong&gt; That’s not an issue at all. See the FAQs below. All you need to join up is your desire to boost your health.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Send me feedback.&lt;/strong&gt; I’m gonna try to make everything accessible and welcoming, but I’m still a middle-aged white dude with his own stuff. Hold me accountable! Contribute or post issues to the repo! Everybody wins!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;faqs-partially-borrowed-based-on-100-days-of-code-and-then-tweaked&quot;&gt;FAQ’s Partially Borrowed Based on 100 Days of Code and Then Tweaked&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q:&lt;/strong&gt;The public part of this troubles me. What should I do?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;A:&lt;/strong&gt;Whatever works best for you. Really. I mean, I’d love to hear it if you are participating, and letting people in your life know you’re doing this can be super powerful. A casual “how’s the 100 days going?” is super motivating! But! Getting 3+ months of awesomeness privately is better than not doing it because of the public component.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q:&lt;/strong&gt; I’ve missed a day, does it mean I’ve failed the challenge?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;A:&lt;/strong&gt; Absolutely not. Do your best to only miss one day every two weeks. Never miss two days in a row (so you can’t skip the 14th day of one week period and the 1st day of another). Alex mentions that he got this great piece of advice on habit formation from Leo Babauta at &lt;a href=&quot;http://zenhabits.net/&quot;&gt;zen habits&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q:&lt;/strong&gt; I come home late, and by the time I am finished with my hour, it’s past midnight. Does it count?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;A:&lt;/strong&gt; Of course it counts! The rule of thumb is: have you taken care of your health or yourself for at least an hour before going to sleep that day? If yes, you are on track. I currently have a 250+ day meditation streak, but sometimes my meditation for the day is at 1:23am. It’s ok.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q:&lt;/strong&gt;How should I track this?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;A:&lt;/strong&gt;Listen, journaling itself could be the self-care you need, so I’m gonna propose you do that (and if you need a journal, let me know; I love my &lt;a href=&quot;https://fieldnotesbrand.com/&quot;&gt;Field Notes&lt;/a&gt; and would love to send you one!). Use the Github repo. Tweet about it.  Whatever is best for you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q:&lt;/strong&gt; If everyone started on a certain day, should I join them on the day they are? For example, from Day 12?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;A:&lt;/strong&gt; Go ahead and start on Day 1. Just mention the day you’re on when you post about it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q:&lt;/strong&gt; What’s a Github?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;A:&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t learn Github just for this project unless you want to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q:&lt;/strong&gt; Why “Healthing” and not “health?”
&lt;strong&gt;A:&lt;/strong&gt; Because internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;helpful-links&quot;&gt;Helpful links&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kungfugrippe.com/post/2572566804/fresh-starts&quot;&gt;Resolutions are stupid&lt;/a&gt; (so let’s make habits instead)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.43folders.com/2011/04/22/cranking&quot;&gt;Cranking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://selfcare.tech&quot;&gt;Selfcare.tech&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;www.shinetext.com/?r=oMPO7gG&quot;&gt;Shine daily motivation texts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://750words.com/&quot;&gt;750 Words&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Una’s great &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/una/personal-goals&quot;&gt;personal goals repo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://healthfinder.gov/FindServices/SearchContext.aspx?topic=833&quot;&gt;US Support Groups&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;Images by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/sachac&quot;&gt;sachac&lt;/a&gt; and licensed under &lt;a href=&quot;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0/&quot;&gt;C.C. by 2.0&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/sachac/17157051896/in/photolist-s97nMA-sfUoL1-9sa2eX-9sd1LL-aatdKM-6PEeVj-dsx3i6-cJYTJC-oMzPb-56CUnd-9sgfe9-fsXK2T-pihpVY-qgL4mF-4f7bev-9TfaLW-ej2mct-gwmN7H-a9MFqY-gwmAC2-jSWVy4-eg9yha-dswhG8-9sgf6f-4FSfTU-aBshrA-nbuAHY-nAKQ4C-zMGBS-9sa2pR-9sge2w-nbtLM7-9sdfhX-jgW5dc-dFHiG5-r1jJAM-6EpzvX-7E3U4g-cjF8mq-5jhfU6-fZDKXs-5HCzhP-9sge6s-drgpAM-9sdfFD-9sgeD5-9FFDea-dPyiC6-9sgfeY-9sdfxp/&quot;&gt;Being extra-kind to myself&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;https://flic.kr/p/rqWndX&quot;&gt;What I do for self care&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;Posted at &lt;a href=&quot;https://unfocused.tech/&quot;&gt;The Unfocused Developer&lt;/a&gt; and on &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@jwithy/100-days-of-healthing-87b2ea71dba9#.5c5z4y4s3&quot;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt; as well. Please spread the word!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Not that I know anything about that. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Oh, another thing to note: I’m fortunate in that I actually &lt;strong&gt;do&lt;/strong&gt; work somewhere that recognizes all the benefits of healthy, happy workers. This project should not imply otherwise. 😄 &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Why public?  Listen to Alex and Saron &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codenewbie.org/podcast/100-days-of-code&quot;&gt;discuss that&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:4&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I’m being vague, too. 😄 &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:4&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://hardlikealgebra.com/2017/01/01/healthing/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hardlikealgebra.com/2017/01/01/healthing/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ten Cubs / Baseball / Life Things</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I work at a job where we are encouraged to write lists of ten as a sort of creative outlet/exercise. I’m also at the point, a day after the Cubs win, where I still get choked up if I read the occasional &lt;a href=&quot;https://theringer.com/chicago-cubs-world-series-father-son-4141678e1cbf#.2c53zu660&quot;&gt;amazing personal essay&lt;/a&gt; about it all.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, here’s Ten Cubs Things that I wrote that are actually, probably, ten life things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I had a basset hound named Wrigley from when he was a puppy until 2014 when he passed away. I got him with the woman I was dating at the time, and we nearly named him Sandberg (after Ryne and Carl). She left a couple of months later, but he stayed with me; she and I are still great friends, and Wrigs was my constant and my buddy who moved with me when I came west and won Erin’s heart as well. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;That same woman used to work with a guy who was a huge Dawson fan. At some point (his 40th bday, maybe?), I gave him all of my Dawson baseball cards that I had collected as a kid. He was visibly shaken and tried to refuse the gift, but I didn’t back down. :-)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I can remember how much the 1984 Cubs captured Illinois; I was only 6 years old but I can picture the construction paper hats we made. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Andre Dawson took a pay cut to move to Chicago (from the Expos) and be part of that team, which lost three straight to the Padres after being up 2-0, knocking them out of the playoffs. I still curse Steve Garvey’s name.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cubs fans at the time loved Jody Davis. My earliest Wrigley Field memory was during just a regular season, whatever game, and anytime he got up to bat, the entire stadium chanted “Jo-dee! Jo-dee!” I’m barely sure why – if you check his career stats, he seems to have been not particularly good.  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;My grandma used to live in Mesa, Arizona, where the Cubs still train. I think maybe we even took family photos at their training ballpark, which at the time was Ho Ho Kam park. I should see if my mom has those photos.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I took a trip to the Field of Dreams in Iowa, and brought a wooden bat (which, even in 2002 or so, was hard to find). Some random guy threw me a pitch and I smacked it into center field. It was glorious.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I played for the vintage base ball team here in Portland, the Portland Pioneer Base Ball Club, for their first few years. I miss playing, but I don’t miss the one guy who had to ruin it by being Very Serious. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I used to tell people that my greatest baseball memory was when I went to a night game at Wrigley, and Kerry Wood came back after 1.5 years out (due to injury) and hit a first pitch home run. I swear the night felt like that scene in The Natural.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Now, I think I’ll tell them my favorite baseball memory is jumping up and cry-screaming with my girlfriend in our living room as Bryant threw to Rizzo and they finally, finally won. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jwithington/jwithington.github.io/master/images/wrigley-field.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Me in front of Wrigley Field&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://hardlikealgebra.com/2016/11/03/10-cubs/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hardlikealgebra.com/2016/11/03/10-cubs/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rebuilding</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m finding myself a bit confused with Erin out of town this weekend, Not really sure what to write about, but I know that I want to write; that I miss this whole writing thing, whatever it is, now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a post that I started in May, right after &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllconf.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Conf&lt;/a&gt;. It was about my job, and how we have labs on Fridays, and we can use them to do “something technology related.” It’s a really cool thing, and one Friday I fixed these here archives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look! If you need to see my &lt;a href=&quot;http://hardlikealgebra.com/lists/2008/01/01/top-ten-albums-for-2007/&quot;&gt;top ten records in 2007&lt;/a&gt;, now you can! &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The archives are a mess because the photos are effed and a bunch of the links are probably wrong. But it feels good to have all of the posts in one place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I spend more of my days coding&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; now, I find myself understanding more things&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. And that leads me to a few paths that probably sound familiar to some people:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I end up going, “oh man! I could probably do that thing programmatically instead of by hand!”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I also then want to do that, which sometimes I can do.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Either way, though, it makes me feel like I &lt;em&gt;need perfection or need to do nothing&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That last one is a pretty bad place to live. It means that I know I want to make my &lt;em&gt;own&lt;/em&gt; template for this blog, not keep using someone else’s. It means that I feel like I need all the accessibility and all the cool CSS things and all the everything before I should launch a thing&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:4&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:4&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been told in the past that I have the bad parts of perfectionism, that maybe that’s what keeps me from Doing a Thing (or at least what propels my procrastination).  If you don’t do a thing, then it’s not gonna be imperfect! Repeat forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yet! And yet and yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew my archive was on a &lt;a href=&quot;https://hardlikealgebra.wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;hastily wired up wordpress site&lt;/a&gt; because at some point I fell out of love with Wordpress and decided to blow it up and archive instead of figuring it all out. Fast forward a few years and plenty of folks have gotten into the whole &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thenewdynamic.org/&quot;&gt;static site&lt;/a&gt; thing. Finding a way to make Wordpress posts into Jekyll posts isn’t so hard anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the tool, the script I used, wasn’t perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it’s not that I can’t be bothered.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s that I &lt;em&gt;won’t&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At least for now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Exclamation points added for sarcasticness. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Mostly in XML, first coding job ever, wish me luck! &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Oh, the insights you’ll go! &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:4&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I even apologize for &lt;a href=&quot;http://tottot.pet&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;, an intentionally sandbox-y, just-try-a-thing site (with my dog, who is admittedly rad). &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:4&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://hardlikealgebra.com/2016/07/02/rebuilding/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hardlikealgebra.com/2016/07/02/rebuilding/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>On Learning Paths and Plans</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;on-learning-plans-and-paths&quot;&gt;On learning plans and paths&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’m learning to code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’ve learned a lot about coding!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’m learning Ruby on Rails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’m writing an RSS app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’m mostly learning JavaScript right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I think I’m going to check out React.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been saying these sorts of things for over a year now.  In between, I got a job at the place I described to people (including my mom) as &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamtreehouse.com&quot;&gt;the place in Portland I’d most like to work&lt;/a&gt;. I met a ton of people, enjoyed the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theatlantic.com/video/index/396527/case-32-hour-workweek/&quot;&gt;four day work week&lt;/a&gt; and then lost my job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t a developer job. I tell people that a lot, at Meetups — &lt;em&gt;no no, don’t be impressed&lt;/em&gt;, it was a customer support-ish job. It was a sales job.  It wasn’t the kind of job that you want to hear about. Really.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This new round of unemployment caused me to find &lt;a href=&quot;http://freecodecamp.com/jwithington&quot;&gt;Free Code Camp&lt;/a&gt;. I love their philosophy, the rigor of learning sorta-solo, and the fact that I had to &lt;em&gt;just figure it out&lt;/em&gt; a whole lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve also stalled out for a few weeks now. I think it’s because coding solo can be scary!  It can be very hard to feel like you accomplished anything when you are trying to build a JavaScript calculator from scratch and but you have no idea what that actually entails.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So then I ended up getting some free months at Pluralsight (that was awesome) and I’ve been learning more on Treehouse (they are still great) and I’ve also signed up on a few &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wayfindingacademy.org/&quot;&gt;awesome&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hackoregon.org/&quot;&gt;projects&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yet I feel like I have this whole cloud of learning that I’m trying to attack all at once, and in the meantime I’m not &lt;a href=&quot;http://skillcrush.com/2016/01/07/41-real-jobs-you-can-get-if-youre-new-to-tech/&quot;&gt;charging anyone for my new skills&lt;/a&gt;. I am applying for jobs that I’m not getting. I see job listings that in a month, three months, hey, by then I should be able to do this, but not quite yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I attended a Code your way to $1K!” webinar last week that was a bit annoyingly centered on selling courses, but it keeps sticking with me. “Code your way to $1K!” has a great ring to it, so of course it drew me in.  I started emailing them to ask about different courses, because I have this weird set of skills where like, I can absolutely host my own jekyll blog on Github, and I can scaffold a new Rails app, yet I’m not sure I could set up my own CSS for a site without it looking like a chump built &lt;a href=&quot;http://jimwithington.com&quot;&gt;my website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, their support was super helpful. And they heard I was unemployed and found a way to make it work better for me, cost-wise. They are smart about saying things like “charge for the skills you are building,” and making me feel like they will give me the tools to find paying work. And maybe taking on some freelance work is actually what’s in store for me. Maybe I’ll get to redesign the Fire on the Mountain website or Erin’s preschool’s site someday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think they may have won me over.  I have to see a bit about some other stuff (especially with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hackoregon.org/&quot;&gt;Hack Oregon&lt;/a&gt;), because I’m an impulsive joiner to a fault and all this learning needs to not interfere with actually getting paid work again (temp work, freelance work with new skills, office work, WHATEVER WORK).   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But  I’m also on an accelerated timeframe.  I don’t want to wait another month. I don’t want to piece together things.  I like the idea of a learning path that I paid for and that centers around “get paid for what you know.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because doing it on my own I am not sure of what I know.  Doing it within their system?  I can trust that they &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that might just be the confidence I need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;edited to add: I wrote this posted on the date above. Since then, things have changed a lot: a friend has helped me focus my efforts, I stopped working with Hack Oregon, I signed up for Skillcrush and have been super happy with it, and I’ve even gotten a job! On March 30, 2016, I decided to go ahead and post this, because it’s a good record of where I’ve been and where I’m going.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Note that shortly after I wrote this, they made sweeping changes to the curriculum and re-ordered the projects to hopefully prevent this problem. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Worth pointing out that the current CSS over there is basically just the exported html from Byword.  Effective, but possibly chump-like. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://hardlikealgebra.com/2016/02/10/learning-paths/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hardlikealgebra.com/2016/02/10/learning-paths/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Five Early Portland Memories</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/21/26410870_b790044036_z.jpg?zz=1&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; alt=&quot;what up internet jack.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Gladstone apartment mornings. Always looking for the Harold bus to get to work.  Make sure to walk Wrigley, eat some breakfast. Call the Trimet line to see when the 10 will arrive. Sometimes look out the window, see the bus pull up, still get there in time.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The Fremont hill of doom. I finally bike all the way up, about 30 blocks of solid incline. This is the most in shape I’ve ever been as a cyclist, back when all of my friends were scrappy as hell, vegetarian, biked everywhere, made zines, played games.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;10am in the middle of the summer and I’m biking across town to play Risk 2210 with Franco and Joe and another Joe. I feel like a kid again, pedalling across town to friends and games. Who needs full time work and all that when I can do this and still make my bills?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;On the phone with Erin. I’m looking for my first ever solo apartment, because she’s planning to live and work in Portland for the summer. I’ve never signed a real lease. I’m going to plan to pay for it myself, just in case. She tells me that if I can afford it, go ahead and get something. We ended up there for over 2 years.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I’ve got a temp job doing taxes for folks, or rather, printing and assembling documents for them.  It’s a process that involves spreading the documents put in a particular way, all the way across a very long counter, and then stapling them into a folder. I see Ursula K. Le Guin is one of their clients. Every time I’m ever looking for work again, I think of this job, of the joy of podcasts all day and the rhythm of stapling and how much it felt like good, hard, honest, appreciated work.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm1.staticflickr.com/21/26065809_659148449a_z.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Plaid Pantry sign&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://hardlikealgebra.com/2016/02/03/five-early-portland-memories/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hardlikealgebra.com/2016/02/03/five-early-portland-memories/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Starting to *get* it</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m working over on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.freecodecamp.com/&quot;&gt;freecodecamp&lt;/a&gt; now, learning JavaScript with a few goals:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;finish their program in Front End, Full Stack, and soon, &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.freecodecamp.com/learn-to-code-by-coding-d1e241de81c0#.3kahg68km&quot;&gt;Data Visualization and Backend&lt;/a&gt; work&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;work on their non-profit projects (for a better world!) so that &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I can build projects that help me get work in the field (for a better me!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I was working on one of their algorithm challenges (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.freecodecamp.com/map#basic-algorithm-scripting&quot;&gt;Bonfires&lt;/a&gt;, in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.freecodecamp.com/&quot;&gt;FCC&lt;/a&gt;-speak). It’s [an exercise in truncating strings][trunc] that I’d started last night and had some success with, but I’d set it down to work on it today (and because Erin and I wanted to watch some &lt;em&gt;Casual&lt;/em&gt;, which is a Show I Have Mixed Feelings About But Still Is Worth Watching).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was able to figure it out in a way that made me really feel like I’m starting to &lt;em&gt;get&lt;/em&gt; this. Not just parroting what others show me; really building my skills. It’s a rush, and it’s really exciting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the code. It’s yet another start in my world of starts. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&quot;https://gist.github.com/anonymous/25516460412e7af66feb.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[trunc]: http://www.freecodecamp.com/challenges/bonfire-truncate-a-string#?solution=function%20truncate(str%2C%20num)%20%7B%0A%20%20%2F%2F%20Clear%20out%20that%20junk%20in%20your%20trunk%0A%20%20if%20(num%20%3C%3D%203)%20%7B%0A%20%20%20%20str%20%3D%20str.slice(0%2C%20num)%20%2B%20’…‘%3B%0A%20%20%7D%20else%20if%20(num%20%3E%3D%20str.length)%20%7B%0A%20%20%20%20return%20str%3B%0A%20%20%7D%20else%20%7B%0A%20%20%20%20str%20%3D%20str.slice(0%2C%20num%20-3)%20%2B%20’…‘%3B%0A%20%20%7Dreturn%20str%3B%0A%7D%0Atruncate(%22A-%22%2C%201)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://hardlikealgebra.com/2015/12/11/starting-to-get-it/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://hardlikealgebra.com/2015/12/11/starting-to-get-it/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
